The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
Fullmetal!
鋼の
He disappeared?!
消えた
What did you do?!
何をした
He was simply escorted to a place
you'll eventually arrive at yourself.
君がいずれ赴くべき所へ
運ばれていっただけだ
What the hell is this?
なんだよ　これ
This sensation...
この感じは…そうだ
That's right!
The same sensation I got when I opened the Gate of Truth!
真理の扉を開けたときと同じだ
Dammit!
くそっ　貴様
You son of a bitch!
You're...!
お前
Idiot!
バカ野郎　こっちはほっとけ
Leave this place to us!
It's our duty...
若をお守りするのが…
...to protect the young master.
我らの仕事…
It's impossible to carry this much weight with an automail!
機械鎧でこの重さを支えるのは無理だ
Worry about your grandfather instead!
お前はじいさんの心配を…
It's...
もう　間に合わない…
...too late.
Briggs soldiers, lend me a hand!
ブリッグズ兵　手を貸せ
Right!
ブラッドレイ　くらえ
Bradley, eat this!
Fu!
フー
Fu!!
Someone call a doctor!
誰か　医者を
Are there any doctors well-versed in alchemy?!
錬金術を使える医者はいないのか
I've...
ここに　賢者の石がここにあるんだ
I've got a philosopher's stone right here!
Use as much of it as you need!
いくらでも使ってくれ
Anyone!
誰か　頼む　ここは錬金術大国
Please!
Isn't Amestris the land of alchemy?!
アメストリスだろ
There's gotta be someone here!
誰かいないのか
Hey!!
Why...?
なんでだ…
Why...
なんで…
Young master!
若
You monster...
化け物め…
Why...
なんでだ…
I can't save a single vassal despite achieving immortality...?
不老不死を手に入れても
臣下一人救えないのかよ…
Fuck!!
くっそ
Captain!
大尉
大尉　気をしっかり　大尉
Captain, get yourself together!
Captain!
Captain!!
大尉
Fire!
撃て
We were able to give Bradley a fatal wound thanks to you.
あなたのお陰で
ブラッドレイに
致命傷を負わせられた
Even though you ensured that Fu's death would not be in vain,
フーの死が
ムダではなくなったというのに
I can't even do a thing to help you.
オレはあなたに何もしてやれない…
Give me ammo!
弾をくれ
That was the last round!
それで最後だ
Shit!
くそっ　こっちも弾切れです
I'm out too!
Everyone, fire back with your rifles!
各自　銃で応戦しろ
Roger!
はい
Lin Yao...
リン·ヤオ…
Or Greed, whichever you are...
グリード…どっちでもいい
If you're truly thankful, would you mind doing me a favor?
恩義に思ってるなら
一つ頼まれてくれんか
We're not supposed to let this gate open until our Queen orders it to be.
この扉…
うちの女王様の命令があるまで
開けられんことになってんだ…
Please, protect it...
頼む　守ってくれ…
It should be possible with your strength...
お前の力なら　やれるだろう…
No, only you... can do it...
いや…
お前にしかできないから頼む…
I'm begging you...
Greed.
グリード
Yo?
I want power.
力が欲しい　貸してくれ
Lend me some.
Sure thing.
いいぜ　こっちの予定まで
We've still got some time until my next plan.
あと少し時間がある
Lan Fan, you protect the people here.
ランファンはここの者たちを守れ
Roger!
Could you... do that for me?
やって…くれるか
Yeah, I promise.
約束する
People from Xing...
シンの人間は…
...never break alliances!
盟約を必ず守る
Fire! Fire!
撃て撃て
W-Who the hell is that?!
なっ　なんだ　あいつは
All right, listen up!
いいか　よく聞け
Those who don't wish to get hurt,
ケガをしたくない者
and those who have family and lovers, stand back!
家族  恋人のいる者は下がれ
And women, too!
あと　女
オレは女と戦う趣味はねぇ
I don't particularly enjoy fighting women!
No way...!
バカな…
Fire!!
Incredible...
すごい…リン·ヤオ
Lin Yao.
Or should I say, Homunculus?
いや　人造人間か
How promising they are once you have one on your side...
味方に付けると なんと頼もしい
Captain!
大尉　大尉
Captain, please hang in there!
大尉　しっかりしてください
Did he... join our side?
あいつは味方になってくれたのか
Yes, sir!
はい
Now I can kick the bucket in peace...
これで安心してくたばれる…
何を言ってるんですか　大尉
What are you saying, Captain?!
Major General Armstrong will achieve victory soon!
もうすぐアームストロング少将が勝ちます
Just a little longer!
あと少しです
大尉にはセントラルで今まで以上に
We need you to take an even more active role in Central than ever before!
活躍していただかないと
I don't like the sooty sky here in Central...
セントラルのすすけた空は肌に合わん…
Farewell, comrades...
さらばだ　同志…
I'll go on ahead...
先に…行ってるぞ…
...to an even higher place than the summit of Briggs...
ブリッグズの峰より
少し高い所へ…
Captain Buccaneer!!!
バッカニア大尉
What was that flash of light from before?
さっきの光はなんだったんだ
なんの発表もないな
There hasn't been a single announcement.
What's going on with military headquarters?
どうなってるんだ  軍司令部は
No follow-up reports from Radio Capital?
ラジオ·キャピタルの続報はないの
Nope.
ないねぇ
What about the other stations?
ほかの局は
They're just announcing a curfew for the moment.
外出禁止を呼びかけてるだけだよ
Mommy!
ママ
The radio tells us we can't go outside,
外に出ちゃダメって
ラジオで言ってるから
タバサちゃん家は
so let's hold off on going to Tabasa's house today, okay, Elicia?
あきらめましょうね　エリシア
What?!
We can see the solar eclipse from here, too.
ここからでも見えるわよ
It's about to begin,
もうすぐ始まるから
so let's watch it from here with Mommy.
ママと一緒に見ようね　日食
イズミ
Izumi!
どこだ　イズミ
Where are you?!
Izumi!!
アレックス
Alex, do you know what just happened?
どういうことか分かるか
I heard this from the Elric Brothers in the past.
以前　エルリック兄弟に
聞いたことがあります
人体錬成をしたとき
They said that when they performed human transmutation,
they were dragged into the Gate of Truth by black hands.
黒い手によって
真理の扉に引きずり込まれたと
What is this "Gate of Truth" you speak of?
真理の扉とはなんだ
分かりません
I have no idea.
What did you say?!
なんだって
連絡がついたのか
Were you able to get in touch with them?
閣下　本部は無事です
Major General, headquarters is safe.
Good.
よし
で　イズミさんに関する情報は
And, did you obtain any information pertaining to Miss Izumi's situation?
何かあったか
いえ…
No...
I see...
そうか
ほかには
And what else?
正門を守っていた
During a battle with King Bradley,
バッカニア大尉が部下数名とともに
Captain Buccaneer, who was defending the main gate,
キング·ブラッドレイとの
戦闘において…
死亡しました
lost his life along with a few other men.
大尉はシン国の者と協力し
It has been reported that the captain,
working together with someone from Xing,
successfully gave Bradley a fatal wound and knocked him down into a canal.
ブラッドレイに致命傷を与え
堀に突き落としたそうです
バカな…
Impossible!
バカな　バカな　バカな
There's no way that can be true!
あのキング·ブラッドレイが
How could that King Bradley die so easily?!
そんな簡単に死ぬものか
あれは人外の…
He's not human-
正門はどうなった
And what about the main gate?
It's still being defended.
まだ守られています
グリードとかいう人造人間が
A homunculus by the name of Greed joined their side,
味方に付き
and tore apart the central soldiers at the main gate.
正門中央兵をなぎ倒しました
A homunculus?!
人造人間が
Impossible.
バカな　人造人間が
A homunculus would never turn its fangs on that man...
あのお方に刃向かうなど…
バッカニア大尉は
Apparently, Captain Buccaneer passed away with a smile.
笑って逝かれたそうです
I see.
そうか…
If he died with a smile, we can't sit here and weep.
ヤツが笑って逝ったのなら
我々が泣くわけにはいかん
Let's proceed!
進もう
はっ
Roger!
シグさん　行きましょう
Let's go, Mr. Sig.
あなたの奥方も捜さねばならない
We also need to look for your wife.
Right.
痛っ…
Ouch...
Oww...
あ痛っ…
師匠
Master!
Ed!
エド
Are you okay?!
大丈夫ですか
Yeah, somewhat.
なんとか
What are you doing here?
なんで師匠がここに
That's what I want to know.
こっちが聞きたいわ
So, where are we?
で　ここはどこなんだ
分かりません
I don't know.
I was just sent here all of a sudden...
いきなり飛ばされて…
Al!
アル
アルまで　もしかして
Hey!
Even Al?
Get yourself together!
Could it be that all the human sacrifices were gathered?
人柱が集められたのか
What's wrong, Al?!
Hey!
One, two, three...
１ ２ ３…
...and four.
４人か…１人足りんな
We're missing one.
あと１人は
I guess the last one is currently being made.
今つくっているところか…
なっ　何なんだ　この化け物は
W-What the hell is this monster?
ホーエンハイム
Hohenheim!
Edward...
エドワード
Even Alphonse was captured...?
アルフォンスまで捕まったのか…
Whoa, Miss Izumi as well.
イズミさんも
Sorry I'm in such a pitiful state.
こんな情けない姿ですまないね…
What in the world is going on?
一体　どういうこと
どうもこうも…
Well...
You stay put.
おとなしくしていろ
お前の中の賢者の石は
I'll slowly absorb the philosopher's stone inside you later.
あとでゆっくり吸収してやる
Who the hell is that dark guy, Hohenheim?!
ホーエンハイム
その真っ黒いヤツは何なんだ
My alter ego.
オレの分身
The guy who the homunculi called 'Father'.
人造人間たちに
お父様と呼ばれていたヤツだよ
こいつがあのヒゲ野郎だってのか
That's the geezer?!
そうなんだ
Yeah.
I was able to destroy his skin, but...
皮袋は壊せたんだが…
Quit your blabbering, Hohenheim.
余計なことはしゃべるな
ホーエンハイム
I welcome you, human sacrifices.
さて　歓迎するぞ　人柱諸君
Thanks for coming to my castle.
ようこそ　私の城へ
アル　起きろ
Al, wake up.
This one's going to be tough.
こいつはヤバそうだぞ
Al?
アル
Hey, Al!
アル　アルフォンス
Alphonse!
The ones up there are so unreliable.
まったく上のヤツらは当てにならんな
They couldn't even prepare five human sacrifices for this day?
この日に合わせて
たった5人の人柱も用意できんとは
まあ  不老不死とか
Well, I gathered all the ones who've been seeking morsels like immortality,
そんな小さい餌に食いついてきた
輩ばかりそろえたのだから
仕事ができなくても当たり前か
so it's no surprise that they couldn't do their jobs.
Damn you!
この…
よし　いいぞ　そのまま
Excellent. Stay just like that.
さてと
Now, Mustang, we don't have much time.
マスタング君　時間がないんだ
進んで協力してくれると有り難い
I'd appreciate it if you could willingly cooperate with me.
君  ちょっと人体錬成して
Do you mind performing human transmutation and opening the gate?
扉を開けてくれないかね
What?
なんだと
誰でもいいよ
I don't care who you transmutate.
亡くなった親　恋人　友人
Your late parents, your lover, your friend.
君と仲がよかった…
The one you were close to...
なんといったっけ
What was his name again?
ヒューズ君
Hughes.
I don't mind if you transmutate him.
あれでもいいよ
We'll take care of all the arrangements.
段取りはこちらでしてあげるから
人柱…というやつか
The ones you call... "human sacrifices"?
Precisely.
そう
Those who open the gate can become human sacrifices.
扉を開けた者が人柱になれるんだ
だからエルリック兄弟が選ばれたのか
So that's why the Elric Brothers were chosen.
Yup.
そうだよ
I heard from them that human transmutation doesn't work.
人体錬成は
成功しないと彼らから聞いた
What idiot would try it when they know it's not going to work?!
失敗すると分かっていて
やるバカがいるか
Good point there.
そうだね
だから　扉さえ開けて
So as long as you open the gate and come back, it's fine.
戻ってきてくれればいい
I refuse!
断る
人体錬成はせん　扉も開けん
I won't perform human transmutation!
I won't open the gate either!
Didn't I tell you that we don't have much time?
言ったよね　時間がないって
中尉
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant?!
中尉　中尉
Lieutenant!
さあ　扉を開けてみようか
Now, open the gate, Mustang.
マスタング君
You scum!!
貴様
Lieutenant! Can you hear me?!
中尉　聞こえるか
返事をするんだ
Say something!
Now, perform human transmutation and become the fifth sacrifice.
さあ　人体錬成をやって
５人目になりたまえ
ほらほら　早くしないと
Come on, if you don't pick up the pace, this woman will die.
この女の命がなくなるよ
Oh, I get it.
そうか　この女が死んだら
You're going to transmute her back after she dies?
錬成するのかね
それでもいいよ
That's fine too.
I won't die...
死なないわ…
I've been ordered not to die...
私はね…命令で
死ねないことになってるのよ…
そんなので
If one could obtain an immortal body with an order like that,
死なない体が手に入るなら
everyone would live without worry.
人間　苦労しないよ
What will you do, Mustang?
マスタング君　どうするね
君の大事な女が死にかけている
A woman who's precious to you is dying.
If you leave her be, she'll die from blood loss.
ほうっておけば　すぐ失血死
だが
But I'm a doctor well-versed in alchemy,
私は錬金術が使える医者で
and tadaa, I even have a philosopher's stone.
なんと賢者の石まで持っている
つまり　私なら　この女の命を
In other words, I can save this woman's life.
確実に救うことができる
ということだ
Well, if she dies before you make a decision, there'll be nothing I can do.
まあ　君が決断する前に死んでしまえば
私にもどうすることもできないけどね
Oh?
She's gotten quiet.
おとなしくなったね
死んでしまったのかなぁ
I wonder if she died.
Colonel...
大佐…
There's no need... for you to perform human transmutation.
人体錬成なんて…
する必要は…ありません
You'll do it, won't you, Mustang?
するでしょ　マスタング君
Now!
さあ
分かった
I will.
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Though there may be favorable turn,
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
Fullmetal  Alchemist
know that this repose last but a moment.
第５９話　『失われた光』
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
The place upon which thou standest is the entrance to the netherworld.
終わりの時が始まる
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 59, Lost Light.
The end is near.